# **Joseph Randazzo**

2330 Edenburn Drive Apt. C Ames, IA 50010 224-216-7774 joeyrandazzo@gmail.com

# **Objective**

# Software Engineering/Application Development Employment

I am passionate about science, math, and software; having utilized it all my life and graduating with a degree in software engineering from Iowa State.

Personally, I am **flexible and reactive**, and actively mitigate downtime. I am exceptionally **personable**; having worked with people of all ages and backgrounds. I seek out to resolve engaging and challenging situations. I am **ready to learn more**, highly coachable, self-motivated, and open to new experiences.

Long-term, I would like to do something both engaging and gratifying. I would like to explore and utilize people and technology, one day becoming a **highly successful project manager**.

Given the opportunity and knowledge, I am known to get things done; quickly and correctly.

### **Education**

# Software Engineering, Class of 2017

Fall '13 - Spring '17

Iowa State University | Ames, IA

Bachelor of Engineering, Bachelor of Liberal Arts and Sciences

Out of six large group projects, I was **team leader and main developer** for four of them and designed, coordinated meetings, and performed thorough documentation for the other two. Designed, installed and troubleshot **smart home devices** for **Android** and **Amazon** products as well as designing and implementing computer and mobile applications for drones and entertainment. Focused on **artificial intelligence** and advanced mathematics to challenge myself.

GPA: 3.44

#### **Relevant Coursework**

- **Software Engineering:** Software Architecture, Design & **Project Management**, Software Construction & User Interface, Software Evolution and Maintenance, Senior Design
- Computer Science: Database Management Systems, Programming & Data Structures, Software Project Management, Object-Oriented Analysis and Design, Algorithm Analysis, Software Testing, Principles of Artificial Intelligence, Intro to Computational Geometry
- **Computer Engineering:** Computer Organization & Assembly Programs, Digital Logic & Embedded Systems, Intro to & Theoretical Foundations of Computer Engineering, Operating Systems

# **Programming Languages and Current Knowledge**

- **Java** used in most software engineering and computer science courses, very familiar.
- **C** and **C++**, C used in most computer engineering courses, understand and efficiently use memory and pointers. C++ covered in a one semester course.
- **C#** and Gradle with Android Studio and Unity
- MySQL, JQuery, XML for databasing, notably relative strength compared to other students.
- HTML, PHP, CSS, JavaScript, some Python used in some personal web development and debugged for some projects.

### **Experience**

# **Software Support**

March '19 - Current

Ortho2 | Ames, IA

Supporting orthodontic software with a small company with big reach. Taking calls and working with advanced supports, on-site technicians, and developers to fix issues. Consistently and efficiently following up on all calls.

# **Independent Game Developer**

August '16 - Current

Self-Employed | Various

**Self-taught** Unity and C# for scripting to design and create games with fiancé and colleagues in free time. Planning on publishing first **ambitious** game in Summer of 2019. Additionally, doing mathematics and engine work for various indie games coming soon to Android and PC, as well as documenting and cleaning up old Unity codebases and converting JavaScript to C#.

### **Mathematics Tutor**

September '18 - Current

Mathnasium | Ankeny, IA

Efficient math tutoring; assisting with packets, paperwork, and students ages K-12. Topics educated include: Algebra, calculus, statistics, geometry, analysis, probability, graph theory, and topology.

# Independent Mentor/Teacher's Aid

February '18 – May '19 Iowa Net High Academy & Tutorcare | Ames, IA **Mentored underprivileged** high school students and disabled veterans in the university. Tutoring geometry, biology, forensics, statistics, computer science, and general engineering. **Broadband Specialist** 

May '17 - November \17

Mediacom | Ames, IA

Installed and maintained cable television, phone, and internet services. Drove a company van, went into customer homes, and **represented the company in a professional, friendly manner**. Learned and performed a variety of duties including maintenance, change of service, additional outlet installation, disconnection of service, payment collection, and other special requests.

### **Activities & Interests**

- 2018-Current **Dungeons & Dragons** (Dungeon Master) Bi-weekly organization of players and campaign stories and goals.
- 2016-Current **ISU Anime Club** (Council Assistant) Organization and upkeep of tasks.
- 2014 ISU Computer Science and Software Engineering Club (CSE Club)
- 2009-2013 **Astronomy Club** (President) Organized several trips to the Adler Planetarium, discussed and shared news about astronomy, space, and astrophysics.
- 2009-2011 **Robotics Club** Designed and prototyped various frames and mechanisms.
- 9 years of guitar and bass guitar, former hobbyist in online video creation.

#### **Awards & Scores**

- 2018 NCRC Platinum 7: Perfect score in each category
- F2015, S2016, F2016 Iowa State University Dean's List
- 2016-2017 Award for Competitive Excellence
- **34 ACT** composite score, **36 ACT** in math and science

### **Reference Contact Information**

- Fillthecup Games Lead Designer: Chloe Enos 515-329-5444 enoschloe@gmail.com
- Iowa Net High Academy CEO, Supervisor, and Mayor of Hope County: Cynthia Knight 515-829-2336 dr.knight@nethigh.org
- Illinois Shelter & Recovery Services Supervisor: John Couleur 224-616-1686 jcouleur@gmail.com